<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[The Long Road]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.hectoregm.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.hectoregm.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-19T23:03:54-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.hectoregm.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Hector E. Gomez Morales]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[hectoregm@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summer of Learning]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hectoregm.com/blog/2013/06/19/summer-of-learning/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-19T23:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hectoregm.com/blog/2013/06/19/summer-of-learning</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Several years ago I was part of Google Summer of Code for Mono, my
project was building a WYSIWYG documentation editor for the .NET
API. I learned a lot about GTK# and GUI development during that summer
that enabled me to make a functional editor.</p>

<p>The key to the success of that summer is that I had a very
concrete goal: a working editor. So this year I think I can
get even better results by having again a very concrete goal:
A web/iOS task management application based in the <a href="http://www.pomodorotechnique.com/">Pomodoro
Technique</a></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The Pomodoro Technique is very simple and easy to understand:</p>

<ol>
<li> Choose a task to accomplish</li>
<li> Set a timer to 25 minutes</li>
<li> Work on the task until the timer rings</li>
<li> Mark that a pomodoro is done.</li>
<li> Take a short break (5 min)</li>
<li> Go to step 1</li>
</ol>


<p>This group of steps form the Tracking stage as defined in <a href="http://pragprog.com/book/snfocus/pomodoro-technique-illustrated">Pomodoro
Technique
Illustrated</a>,
this stage is the essence of the technique but is not the whole process.
While implementing solely this stage enhances greatly your productivity in
my experience the other stages (Planning, Recording, Processing and
Visualizing) provide a clear picture of the weak and strong points of
your work rhythm. Almost all the apps in App Store around the
technique focus mainly in the Tracking stage.</p>

<p>In my opinion a great application should tell about how good your
estimates are for recurring tasks, tell how many interruptions you had
and at what time of the day are more frequent, given your pomodoro
velocity (your average pomodori per day) how long will be to finish
all your backlog, etc.</p>

<p>Enter the iPad, I got one last December, it has been a great tool
giving me easy access to great productivity apps like Omnifocus,
iStudiez Pro, Dropbox and Lift. All of them have made a great impact
on my workflow through the day. So this summer I am learning iOS app
 development to build a great app that not only keeps tracks of the
 pomodoro you are working on but that I can provide insights
 to your work rhythm.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Beginning]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hectoregm.com/blog/2013/06/09/new-beginning/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-09T23:06:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hectoregm.com/blog/2013/06/09/new-beginning</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I think having a blog is helpful is several ways:</p>

<ul>
<li>Forces you to wrap your head around the topics you want to write
about.</li>
<li>Helps you to measure your progress and what you still need to improve.</li>
<li>English is not my native language so any opportunity to improve my
writing skills is excellent.</li>
</ul>


<!-- more -->


<p>Writing a blog is a hard job, but I have arrived to a stage in my
life that I need a place where I can store that one-liner that makes
wonders, reflections of the articles and books I am reading and
tutorials of things that took a tooth and nail to get working.</p>

<p>My posts will focus on Ruby, Rails, Objective-C, iOS, Rubymotion and
Computer Science in general.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
